<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Creative Industry on Simon Peng 🐒</title>
    <link>https://simonpeng.net/categories/creative-industry/</link>
    <description></description>
    
    <language>en</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 11:07:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/01/27/we-have-to-stop-pretending.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 11:07:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/01/27/we-have-to-stop-pretending.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/we-have-to-stop-pretending-creativity&#34;&gt;We have to stop pretending creativity is &amp;ldquo;magic.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;
I feel like the only way to build solidarity for creative labour is by sharing your process and making it clear that you &lt;strong&gt;aren’t&lt;/strong&gt; magically talented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#art #creativity #process&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2024/09/24/after-taking-some.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 08:02:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2024/09/24/after-taking-some.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After taking some time away from writing and making things, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking a lot about how much pressure we put on ourselves to show up all of the time. Is it even fair for us to expect that of ourselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/are-we-entitled-to-our-own-creativity&#34;&gt;www.everyonescreative.net/p/are-we-&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2024/07/23/every-time-a.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 13:12:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2024/07/23/every-time-a.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time a company like Adobe introduces new “features,” it’s an attempt to make leaving them harder.  
“AI” tools &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; empowering, just not for you. They empower the companies that offer them by making you rely less on yourself and more on the company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2024/07/09/new-post-on.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 08:20:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2024/07/09/new-post-on.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New post on Everyone’s Creative exploring the unnecessary “AI” features being crammed into everything, how Adobe doesn’t care about you, and what we give up when we sell off the one thing we don’t need computers to help with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/ai-companies-think-youre-stupid&#34;&gt;www.everyonescreative.net/p/ai-comp&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts on Adobe (with many more to come)</title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2024/07/04/some-thoughts-on.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 15:17:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2024/07/04/some-thoughts-on.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already wrote about why I left the company, but to sum up: the business changed and I didn’t like/support these changes, I wanted to reconnect with my community of art and illustration friends/colleagues, and I wanted to work on things that mattered to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://accidental-expert.com/p/hello-procreate&#34;&gt;Kyle Webster, &lt;em&gt;Hello, Procreate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discourse around Adobe recently has highlighted what I have been saying about artists being at odds with corporations. While Adobe’s recent PR messes are worth being upset about, I think it’s important we realize how small of a change it was — they were already so misaligned from the values and needs of most of the artists forced to use their tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s illuminating to hear that the company has shifted so much that it’s driving such important artists away. A boon for Procreate, but a real black mark on Adobe. What does it say about your culture and priorities when this is the reason people cite for leaving?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adobe is such a perfect case study in how to squander a reputation and burn bridges. But more than that, they represent a lesson we should all take away as artists: don’t let yourself become dependant on tools or companies. Your power is in your ability to create — not to create with something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I just feel like we need to say this all the time: don’t take anything companies or CEOs say at face value. Adobe will always say they value artists because we are the only reason they exist — but what do their actions say?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>