<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Peng 🐒</title>
    <link>https://simonpeng.net/</link>
    <description></description>
    
    <language>en</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 10:58:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/29/the-cbc-logo-is-so.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 10:58:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/29/the-cbc-logo-is-so.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The CBC logo is so crazy iconic. It’s odd to feel patriotic about branding but Canadians have it pretty good in this regard. CBC, the (formerly public) CN Rail brand, the Canadian flag 🇨🇦 There’s a lot of great design baked into our nation and there’s probably something to be said about how that used to bring us together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.logohistories.com/p/cbc-logo-1974&#34;&gt;www.logohistories.com/p/cbc-log&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting that the worst design I saw from the big parties during the election was pretty clearly all from the conservatives, who are also the most polarizing and populist voice in our politics right now. Does good design tend to lean centre-left? Some of the most iconic poster design I can think of is explicitly communist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does bad design make people feel less united? I personally know I don’t want to be identified with things that are just objectively ugly or incompetent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can design help heal the divide we’re seeing politically around the world? I feel like that’s a big ask.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/28/i-have-had-to-dip.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 14:51:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/28/i-have-had-to-dip.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had to dip back into working with Adobe applications a bit, and am having the &amp;ldquo;pleasure&amp;rdquo; of using Microsoft Office programs to set up templates for clients. Both are amazing me with these little features I look for only to find out they&amp;rsquo;re known issues with many years of people requesting them and the general response to the request is just &amp;ldquo;Unfortunately, that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist :( Sorry!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aren&amp;rsquo;t these two of the biggest software companies on earth? It&amp;rsquo;s almost like their primary interest &lt;em&gt;isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; in making their tools better for the people that use them&amp;hellip; 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/26/with-so-many-big-existential.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 09:42:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/26/with-so-many-big-existential.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With so many big, existential issues going on all the time it feels like there’s no space to enjoy the things that we do. But if you never have any fun, you aren’t going to want to do anything, and nothing is going to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, whatever you’re doing, remember to try to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/this-is-the-secret-to-actually-making&#34;&gt;have fun!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/23/today-in-being-an-overenthusiastic.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:56:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/23/today-in-being-an-overenthusiastic.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today in being an over-enthusiastic Linux beginner: made a typo in the terminal and accidentally rewrote the permissions of every file in my system and destroyed the operating system. Fun! This is why you make backups, I guess!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/21/as-more-and-more-people.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 12:31:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/21/as-more-and-more-people.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As more and more people seem to be blindly accepting that AI belongs everywhere, whether it makes any sense or not, I think it’s important to demystify AI more and talk about the people trying to push for this future. Who does it actually benefit? What do they value? Why are we just going along with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great interview and a very revealing conversation about the company behind some of the most popular AI products today. If you use AI tools, you should understand where (and who) they come from before you make them an indispensable part of how you work and think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloodinthemachine.com/p/dismantling-the-empire-of-ai-with&#34;&gt;www.bloodinthemachine.com/p/dismant&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/21/did-you-know-ireland-launched.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 12:29:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/21/did-you-know-ireland-launched.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know Ireland launched a basic income pilot just for artists? €325/week for 3 years. Not charity—it&amp;rsquo;s recognition that art is essential work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://substack.com/@shagunsingh/note/c-111837880?&#34;&gt;via Shagun Singh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if we eliminated the middle-man and artists didn’t need to beg for money on Patreon and justify the (commercial) value of their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should all want to cultivate a rich culture. Arts funding should go hand-in-hand with science funding. We can’t say what the tangible benefits of space exploration or creative exploration will be but they both can yield results nobody could plan for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/19/recognize-that-creativity-is-neither.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:03:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/19/recognize-that-creativity-is-neither.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Recognize that creativity is neither good nor evil - but that it is powerful. You are responsible for your ideas and for what you create. Remember that you can cause great harm - by accident or by choice. You need to choose not to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/be-careful-you-might-be-causing-more&#34;&gt;Create with Care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/18/i-didnt-feel-much-when.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 09:07:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/18/i-didnt-feel-much-when.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn’t feel much when I deleted my Facebook account. I mostly felt fatigue when I deleted my Twitter. But deleting my Reddit account feels so freeing. I don’t know why I felt like there was any value in reading the thoughts of anonymous idiots on every little topic. It’s madness. Get out of there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/16/ive-been-pushing-myself-to.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:27:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/16/ive-been-pushing-myself-to.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pushing myself to use more open source software, but for graphic design work I still feel very trapped with either Adobe or Affinity. That said, I&amp;rsquo;m working with Inkscape and I&amp;rsquo;m not having a &lt;em&gt;horrible&lt;/em&gt; time. It&amp;rsquo;s clunky, but also capable (once you figure out where things are buried).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/manifesto-part8thumbnail.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/05/16/today-is-a-nice-day.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:02:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/05/16/today-is-a-nice-day.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is a nice day to learn that old workplace safety manuals have some pretty hilarious images when you take them out of context!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/supervisorssafet0000unse/page/161/mode/1up&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/safetymanual-faceshield.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;401&#34; alt=&#34;Old black and white photo of a man with a face shield on, next to the same man splattered in... something.&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/safetymanual-dummy.png&#34; width=&#34;591&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of a manequin that is decorated with the same injuries occuring in the workplace.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is AI a threat? Or does it just expose the existing threats?</title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/04/30/is-ai-a-threat-or.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 14:04:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/04/30/is-ai-a-threat-or.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI will outpace humans in all structured tasks. If you’re producing repeatable deliverables, you will be automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.substack.com/pub/beinginspace/p/ai-and-money&#34;&gt;Being in Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t disagree with this take, but I do wonder if anyone willingly finds themself in the “repeatable deliverables” situation of their own volition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of the same things in my work, but over-optimizing a system and doing things exactly the same way every day becomes so boring and soulless. I’m constantly re-working how I arrive at a finished product and that in turn refines what I make (the quality and the process and experience of the making).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before factories and mass-production and Taylorism, things were much more freeform. Craftspeople built their own tools and constantly reimagined what they did. Art and “production” are only different when someone else is forcing you to produce repetitively and in a standardized way. That’s where you become replaceable: when you’re just a stand-in for a machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with so many other issues, is AI showing us where we need to pivot in order to stay relevant or is it revealing to us where the exploitation and power structures already are in our society?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/04/29/looking-at-the-results-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 08:41:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/04/29/looking-at-the-results-of.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking at the results of our Canadian election is such a mixed bag of emotions. I’m glad to see we haven’t completely fallen into the conservative hell of the US, but the collapse of the NDP feels like we’re on our way into cementing the same two-party system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/04/28/i-looked-at-the-design.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 09:53:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/04/28/i-looked-at-the-design.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I looked at the design of the Canadian political party platforms and what I found wasn’t pretty…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, literally a lot of it was very ugly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/what-your-favourite-political-partys&#34;&gt;www.everyonescreative.net/p/what-yo&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/04/27/i-didnt-like-any-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 20:29:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/04/27/i-didnt-like-any-of.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn’t like any of the off-the-shelf cable management boxes for standing desks because they usually are for when your desk is against a wall. So I made this box that presses into the desk with tension and hides the nasty cables! Fun hand tool project! Still needs finishing, but I like it so far!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/bb17f70751.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;449&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/273302eb67.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;423&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/999f830c55.jpg&#34; width=&#34;590&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/04/02/i-love-working-alone-i.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 09:07:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/04/02/i-love-working-alone-i.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love working alone. 
I think our digital privacy is more important than ever. 
I have also come to believe that individualism is largely overrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/individualism-is-not-a-virtue&#34;&gt;Individualism is Not a Virtue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/03/28/oh-yah-weve-got-cmyk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:57:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/03/28/oh-yah-weve-got-cmyk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OH YAH WE’VE GOT CMYK RUNNING THROUGH 🎆🎇🎉🥳🎊👏👏👏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my PSA for everyone to just attempt fixing your broken shit before you throw it out. If it’s already broken, what’s the worst that could happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…I should probably test the scanner that I actually use way more before I celebrate… 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/38b8ed7132.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/03/28/slowly-reviving-things-but-magenta.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:53:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/03/28/slowly-reviving-things-but-magenta.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly reviving things but Magenta has yet to reappear after I maybe destroyed something… pray for me. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/d4c863b5eb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/03/28/the-one-nice-thing-about.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:47:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/03/28/the-one-nice-thing-about.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The one nice thing about having to completely disassemble your printer to try to unclog it is that you can remove the horrible little speaker that chimes every time you press any button on it and that has no mute function in the settings. 😇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/4323ba33d2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/03/28/so-far-this-printer-repair.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:43:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/03/28/so-far-this-printer-repair.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far this printer repair has slightly increased the amount of black coming through and now completely ruined the colour 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note… did you know the “cleaning” mode of your printer is just it blasting a bunch of ink into sponges inside the printer? I didn’t but it seems funny for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/d8c88dabea.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/03/28/spending-a-not-insignificant-amount.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:39:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/03/28/spending-a-not-insignificant-amount.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spending a not insignificant amount of time trying to repair a long-neglected printer and thinking about how much work this is, how nobody who is sane would do this, and how many fucking printers must be in the landfills so we can all print… what? Movie tickets? Bills?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/04beab2eb6.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;uploads/2025/1b2c79c85b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/03/18/ive-been-trying-to-think.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:12:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/03/18/ive-been-trying-to-think.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to think about how being an artist can help during these wild times in the world. I think it’s really just the same way it always work — we have to share what we make so that other people make things, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/creativity-is-selfish&#34;&gt;www.everyonescreative.net/p/creativ&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/02/21/theres-so-much-negativity-flying.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:40:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/02/21/theres-so-much-negativity-flying.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so much negativity flying around right now and it&amp;rsquo;s starting to really get to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/what-are-we-supposed-to-do-with-all&#34;&gt;What are we supposed to do with all this bad energy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/01/27/we-have-to-stop-pretending.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 11:07:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/01/27/we-have-to-stop-pretending.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/we-have-to-stop-pretending-creativity&#34;&gt;We have to stop pretending creativity is &amp;ldquo;magic.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;
I feel like the only way to build solidarity for creative labour is by sharing your process and making it clear that you &lt;strong&gt;aren’t&lt;/strong&gt; magically talented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#art #creativity #process&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/01/21/you-can-never-separate-the.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:45:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/01/21/you-can-never-separate-the.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🎨 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/you-can-never-separate-the-art-from&#34;&gt;You Can Never Separate the Art from the Artist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#art #creativity&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simonpeng.net/2025/01/04/ive-been-thinking-a-lot.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:10:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://simonpeng.micro.blog/2025/01/04/ive-been-thinking-a-lot.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about the fear people have of AI and the threats it poses to artists. But I feel like there’s one big threat most people are missing: how it will affect the way we work with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everyonescreative.net/p/the-biggest-threat-ai-poses-to-working&#34;&gt;www.everyonescreative.net/p/the-big&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
